Temi Kelani

AWS ARCHITECT temikelani@icloud.com, +1 (646) 854-5958

A Cloud Architect with 3+ years experience architecting, designing, and implementing effective and performant AWS solutions, who enjoys working with companies to architect the most cost-effective and efficient infrastructure for their business needs - using only the tools they need.

CONTACT

- Email
- LinkedIn
- GitHub
- +1 (646) 854-5958
- Remote Anywhere in The World

CERTIFICATES

AWS Associate Solutions Architect

EDUCATION

BENG ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Glasgow Caledonian University United Kingdom 2015

TECH STACK

- Languages: Python, Bash, JavaScript
- OS: Linux
- IAC: CloudFormation, Terraform, Ansible
- CI/CD: GitHub Actions, Circle-CI
- AWS: EC2, Lambda, Auto Scaling, ELB, EBS, S3, VPC, DynamoDB, RDS, SNS, SQS, Event Bridge, CloudFront, CloudWatch, CloudTrail, Config, SSM, IAM, CLI, Route 53, BackUp, CDK
- Containers: ECR, EKS, Docker, Kubernetes,

CAREER HIGLIGHTS

Project Portfolio

A link to featured Projects on GitHub.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AWS Consultant | Upwork | 2020 - Present

Producing custom AWS Lambda scripts including:

- Resource Management: Identifying and deleting unused Resources,
- User Permissions and Management: Adding/Removing User from groups., creating / deleting users
- Filtering resources: Based on custom criteria (tags, SSM, AMI id, region, date/time)
- Automating Resource and DR Backups (EC2, S3, DynamoDB, RDS, EBS): On Demand, Scheduled or Event triggered using DynamoDB, AWS Lambda, Event Bridge Rules, AWS Backup
- Cron Web Scraping Jobs and S3 Data Dumps

Custom configuration (CloudFormation/Terraform) templates for a range of solutions including:

- Monitoring and Alerts via SNS, Cloud Watch, and AWS Lambda
- Configuring multi-AZ/Region fault tolerant solutions architecture

Serverless Architecture

- Deploying Highly Available Apps with EC2, Lambda, CloudFront, API Gateway

Training Cloud Architect | Per Scholas | 2020 - 2021

Per Scholas is an AWS re/Start company that provides real-world, scenario-based learning, labs, and coursework

- Voted team lead
- Built, maintained, and automated the provisioning of cloud infrastructure utilizing nested CloudFormation stacks and GitHub Actions.
- Leveraged AWS cloud services, including EC2, ELB, ASG, and S3, to build and secure scalable and flexible systems designed to handle expected and unexpected load bursts.
- Created, onboarded, and managed users, permissions, directories, and files in Linux environment alongside providing security compliance through automated programmatic remediation using serverless resources, including but not limited to Lambda.
- Built and maintained CI/CD pipeline using AWS CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, CodePipeline, and version control utilizing GIT.
- Conceived, developed, and configured Network infrastructure within VPC with public and private subnets, configured routing tables, security group, and internet gateway.
- Defined and implemented monitoring metrics and logging systems using CloudWatch, Config, and CloudTrail and executed Python script utilizing Crontab.

Data Analyst Intern | Hudson Meridian | 2018 - 2020

I was responsible for maintaining compliance with data at Hudson Meridian, a construction contractor which had to comply with stringent Covid-19 rules to maintain excluded worker status during the pandemic.

- Responsible for Covid-19 data tracking and dashboards resulting in 99% uptime and continued compliance with Department of Buildings Regulations
- Designed and maintained data ingestion pipelines freeing up 40% of the workday
- Monitoring inventory and generated alerts based on volume and for upcoming events
- Maintained database of employees, inventory, and incidents.

_